<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>prometheus on DevCube</title>
    <link>https://rnemet.dev/tags/prometheus/</link>
    <description>Recent content in prometheus on DevCube</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 21:10:05 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rnemet.dev/tags/prometheus/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Example: API Metrics with Prometheus and Grafana</title>
      <link>https://rnemet.dev/posts/k8s/example_implement_metrics_api/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 21:10:05 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnemet.dev/posts/k8s/example_implement_metrics_api/</guid>
      <description>This post is a follow-up to the previous posts on designing metrics for event-driven systems. This humble post is a practical example of how to implement the metrics API and how to use it to create a dashboard in Grafana. I&amp;rsquo;m not using Kubernetes but Docker Compose; the concepts are the same. The reason is simplicity.
The code is available on this GitHub repository.
The Scenario The setup comprises two API services(app and beta) and a database(postgres).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Design Metrics With Prometheus Metric Types: the USE Method</title>
      <link>https://rnemet.dev/posts/k8s/metrics_use_method/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2023 20:38:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnemet.dev/posts/k8s/metrics_use_method/</guid>
      <description>This is the third part of a series about designing metrics for event-driven systems. You can check the first part and the second part of this series before proceeding.
While I discussed the general principles of designing metrics in the first part, I explained Prometheus metric types in the second part. I applied them as the RED method in the second part. In this article, I&amp;rsquo;ll explain the USE method with Prometheus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to Design Metrics With Prometheus Metric Types</title>
      <link>https://rnemet.dev/posts/k8s/metrics_types/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Mar 2023 22:23:12 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://rnemet.dev/posts/k8s/metrics_types/</guid>
      <description>This is the second part of a series about designing metrics for event-driven systems. You can check the first part of this series.
Prometheus is open source system for monitoring and alerting. It is a part of CNCF (Cloud Native Computing Foundation) and it is one of the most popular monitoring systems. You can say it is a de facto standard for monitoring in Kubernetes.
To design metrics with Prometheus, you need to understand its metric types.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
