<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Practical Kubernetes on DevCube</title>
    <link>https://rnemet.dev/posts/practical_k8s/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Practical Kubernetes on DevCube</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- 0.143.1</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 20:46:44 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://rnemet.dev/posts/practical_k8s/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes: Containers, Pods and Deployments</title>
      <link>https://rnemet.dev/posts/practical_k8s/k8s_intro_containers_pods_deployments/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 20:46:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rnemet.dev/posts/practical_k8s/k8s_intro_containers_pods_deployments/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is the second part of the series about Kubernetes. In the &lt;a href=&#34;https://rnemet.dev/practical_k8s/k8s_intro&#34;&gt;first part&lt;/a&gt;,
we introduced the K8s and its basic concepts.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before you start creating services or scaling apps, it&amp;rsquo;s essential to understand
the core components of Kubernetes. This post walks you through pods, containers,
and deployments—what they are, how they work, and how they come together to keep
your apps running smoothly.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;local-setup&#34;&gt;Local Setup&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To taste K8s, you do not need access to some fancy remote platform. You can test
and play with it on your own machine. Right now, there are a lot of solutions that
can help you run K8s locally:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes: A Gentle Introduction for Developers</title>
      <link>https://rnemet.dev/posts/practical_k8s/k8s_intro/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 20:46:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rnemet.dev/posts/practical_k8s/k8s_intro/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Diving into the world of Kubernetes doesn&amp;rsquo;t need to be intimidating. This post
will explain Kubernetes, why it matters, and how it fits into the modern
application landscape. By the end, you&amp;rsquo;ll understand its core purpose and how it
can make your development life more manageable.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The target audience for this post is developers who are new to Kubernetes or those
who work on a product that uses Kubernetes but do not have a deep understanding of it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practical k8s: Pods</title>
      <link>https://rnemet.dev/posts/practical_k8s/pods/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Oct 2022 20:46:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rnemet.dev/posts/practical_k8s/pods/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A Pod would be the smallest deployable unit one can create and manage inside Kubernetes(K8s). In practice, rarely you create a Pod directly.
Instead, one would create a Deployment, a StatefulSet, a DaemonSet, a Job, or a CronJob. These are higher-level constructs that would create
Pods for you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here I&amp;rsquo;m covering common tasks that one would do with a Pod in daily work, like getting logs, opening a shell inside a container, debugging a Pod, etc.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kubernetes: Exposing Services and Horizontal Pod Autoscaler</title>
      <link>https://rnemet.dev/posts/practical_k8s/k8s_intro_svc_hpa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 20:46:44 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://rnemet.dev/posts/practical_k8s/k8s_intro_svc_hpa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is the third part of the series about Kubernetes for beginners. In the
&lt;a href=&#34;https://rnemet.dev/practical_k8s/k8s_intro_pt2&#34;&gt;second part&lt;/a&gt;, I introduced the K8s and its basic
components. In the second part, I discussed containers, pods, and deployments.
This post will discuss services(SVC) and horizontal pod autoscaler(HPA).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In this short post, I will discuss how to expose your services to the outside world
and scale your applications based on the load.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;exposing-deployments-services&#34;&gt;Exposing Deployments: Services&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you create a Deployment, you&amp;rsquo;ll get Pods running your app. So, start local K8s
cluster and deploy an app:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
